<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content><category>Budget and Goals</category><relatedQuiz></relatedQuiz><relatedPoll></relatedPoll><metaTitle>Should I do a 15 year or a 30 year Mortgage?</metaTitle><metaDescription>Purchasing a home can be an exciting and rewarding experience, and foremost, represents the single most important and largest investment...</metaDescription><metaKeywords></metaKeywords><pageTitle>Should I do a 15 year or a 30 year Mortgage?</pageTitle><shortDesc>Purchasing a home can be an exciting and rewarding experience, and foremost, represents the single most important and largest investment...</shortDesc><image>../../assets/images/processed/croppedImg_6486.jpeg</image><temp-contentPage></temp-contentPage><template>article</template><dateModified>08/30/2015</dateModified><contentPage><![CDATA[<p>Purchasing a home can be an exciting and rewarding experience, and foremost, represents the single most important and largest investment in most people&rsquo;s lives.&nbsp; As a result, the process of purchasing a home can be daunting, and if performed carelessly, can be fraught with problems and financial risk.&nbsp; An individual must therefore equip themselves with a strategy and knowledge to prevent a dream from turning into a nightmare.</p>

<p>There are many facets to consider prior to purchasing a home, but one of the most complex and intimidating tasks is evaluating the myriad of financing options.&nbsp; To start, a home buyer must look at themselves in the same perspective a banker will: a quantifiable, risk-based asset that must provide a maximized return.&nbsp; For the most lucrative banking clients, the risk is low and the return is high which results in a large supply of financing offers allowing the client to choose the most competitive.&nbsp; The most competitive offers will be a combination of low interest rates and discounted closing costs.&nbsp; An example of an ideal mortgage loan applicant would have a <a href="http://www.myfico.com/crediteducation/articles/">FICO credit score</a> in excess of 720, a 20% or more down payment, a debt-to-income ratio of less than 36% (less than 36% of the gross income is used to pay a mortgage and recurrent debt), and significant savings and collateral.&nbsp; Bankers also like to make as much money as possible on financing and closing costs to maximize their return.&nbsp; For this reason, bankers prefer low risk applicants with 50-80% loan-to-value mortgages; that is, a large down payment of $145,000 on a $200,000 home would equate to a loan of less than $60,000.&nbsp; Some bankers consider being marginally profitable since fees and interest payments are low.&nbsp; On the other hand, mortgage loan applicants with less than perfect credit, small down payments, or high debt-to-income ratios may have trouble finding banks willing to loan them money.&nbsp; Less than ideal applicants who do manage to find a willing lender will have to pay a premium interest rate due to the higher inherent risk.&nbsp; Therefore, homebuyers must ensure that their financial profile is adequate and acceptable before shopping for financing.</p>

<p>In the mortgage applicant&rsquo;s perspective, not only is it important to have a low interest rate and closing costs, but to have liquidity available for other purchases, and to eventually be able to pay off the mortgage.&nbsp; One factor affecting this decision is to determine whether it is more beneficial to have a 15 year or 30 year mortgage.&nbsp; Intrinsically, the 15 year mortgage will have higher monthly payments but lower overall interest rates throughout the life span of the loan.&nbsp; Let&rsquo;s do a simple example using the mortgage comparison calculator (click <a href="http://www.premierconsumer.org/calculators/mortgage-comparison.php">here</a>) using the following inputs:</p>

<p>Mortgage amount: $100,000</p>

<p>Marginal tax rate: 25%</p>

<p>Interest rate for 15 years: 4%</p>

<p>Interest rates for 30 years: 4.5%</p>

<p>The calculator reveals a $233 difference in payments with a monthly payment of $739.69 for the 15 year mortgage, and $506.69 for the 30 year mortgage.&nbsp; By clicking &ldquo;view report&rdquo; on the mortgage comparison page, it is also evident a significant difference in total interest payments over the life of the</p>

<p>mortgage of $33,144 for the 15 year mortgage versus $82,405 for the 30 year mortgage.&nbsp; It therefore makes sense for home buyers who have the financial means to make the more expensive mortgage payments should opt for the 15 year mortgage and save $49,261 in total interest.</p>

<p>Another strategy that a home buyer can consider is choosing the 30 year mortgage and making additional principle payments when money becomes available.&nbsp; In this way, a home buyer is not bound to a high monthly payment required by the 15 year mortgage which could prove to be a wise choice since no one knows for sure the stability of one&rsquo;s income over a long stretch of time.&nbsp; Therefore, let&rsquo;s do another calculation using the following mortgage payment calculator (click <a href="http://www.bankrate.com/calculators/mortgages/mortgage-calculator.phpx?MSA=4992&amp;MSA=4992">here</a>) using the following inputs:</p>

<p>Mortgage amount: $100,000</p>

<p>Mortgage term: 30 years of 360 months</p>

<p>Interest rate: 4.5%</p>

<p>Extra monthly payments $233</p>

<p>Notice that by making the extra monthly payments equivalent to the difference in our first scenario, the lifespan of the loan is only nine months more than a 15 year mortgage.&nbsp; Additionally, the total interest paid will be $39,754 or $6610 more expensive than the 15 year mortgage.&nbsp; Therefore, for some homebuyers, not being bound to a higher monthly payment with a 30 year mortgage may be more desirable since making extra principle payments is roughly equivalent to the 15 year mortgage though with lowered financial risk and obligation.</p>

<p>Although purchasing a home may seem intimidating and exciting at the same time, using a methodical approach will allow for an objective decision making process.&nbsp; By taking the time necessary to evaluate and scrutinize the options, the benefits of homeownership will pay off in both the short and long-term.&nbsp; It will also provide the individual a nest egg for later in life and can provide assets for one&rsquo;s future generations&hellip;.. Happy House Hunting!</p>
]]></contentPage></content>
