<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content><category>Life Management</category><relatedQuiz></relatedQuiz><relatedPoll></relatedPoll><metaTitle> Fight Stress</metaTitle><metaDescription></metaDescription><metaKeywords></metaKeywords><pageTitle> Fight Stress</pageTitle><shortDesc>People are always complaining about stress. They are tired, fatigued and worn-out. All of that stress has a negative effect on the body...</shortDesc><image>../../assets/images/processed/croppedImg_24750.jpeg</image><temp-contentPage></temp-contentPage><template>article</template><dateModified>09/25/2015</dateModified><contentPage><![CDATA[<p>To get anything worthwhile, a good deal of commitment is necessary. Even marriages today are flimsy,&nbsp; with half ending in divorce. Fight Stress</p>

<p>People are always complaining about stress. They are tired, fatigued and worn-out. All of that stress has a negative effect on the body. It also taxes your mental health and strains relationships. How can you get it under control?</p>

<p><strong>Make Some Cuts</strong><br />
Think about what matters and how much. If you find that every day is a struggle to get it all done, then you have to make some cuts. You will have to quit some activities and give up some responsibilities. Don&#39;t bite off more than you can chew. Your schedule should always be flexible.</p>

<p><strong>Get Organized</strong><br />
The desire to get organized can add to your stress. You mean well when you sit down and create a list of all the things you are going to do, but starting large ends organization before it begins. If you barely have time to breathe now, when are you going to find the time to clean out the garage and alphabetize all of your recipes?</p>

<p>Instead, organize as you go and start small. Create a menu for your weekly meals. Put a calendar beside the phone so you can mark dates and phone numbers; put a schedule on the refrigerator door. Small actions like this save you time and energy by helping you to remember and cutting back on the number of trips you have to make.</p>

<p><strong>Spend Less</strong><br />
If you&#39;re honest, you will admit that a lot of the stress in your life is of your own making. Living beyond your means and out-of-control spending lead to stress. Most of the time, the thing modern people worry about most is money.</p>

<p><strong>Don&#39;t Procrastinate</strong><br />
Keep putting things off and soon you will have something to stress about. A tiny issue you need to take care of becomes bigger and bigger the longer you leave it.</p>

<p><strong>Put Things in Perspective</strong><br />
Besides all of this, there is another key to banishing the stress in your life: relax. People tend to blow things out of proportion. Modern life is a breeze compared to times in the past and scheduling conflicts are better sorted out if you keep calm. So, the car needs fixing? Go grocery shopping tomorrow. Above all, keep your cool.</p>

<p>Stress is a state of mind so dealing with it is about changing the way you look at things. The last thing you want is to look back at your life one day and see that it has passed in a blur of receipts and cell phone calls.</p>
]]></contentPage></content>
