<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content><category>Credit Management</category><relatedQuiz></relatedQuiz><relatedPoll></relatedPoll><metaTitle> Advantages of Buying vs. Renting</metaTitle><metaDescription></metaDescription><metaKeywords></metaKeywords><pageTitle> Advantages of Buying vs. Renting</pageTitle><shortDesc>Please consider the following ten items, and see how many apply to your financial life. If six or more do, it might be a sign...</shortDesc><image>../../assets/images/processed/croppedImg_1321.jpeg</image><temp-contentPage></temp-contentPage><template>article</template><dateModified>09/25/2015</dateModified><contentPage><![CDATA[<p>The fact is that are loan programs that you can apply for, which allow you to purchase a home with very little or even no money down.</p>

<p>We cannot stress how important it is to buy your first home as soon as you can. The benefits are great. Look at the following two sample scenarios:</p>

<table>
	<tbody>
		<tr>
			<td style="background-color:#f1f1f1"><strong>Renting</strong></td>
			<td style="background-color:#f1f1f1"><strong>Buying</strong></td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>$1,200 a month Rent.<br />
			In 12 months you have paid 14,400 that went towards your tenant&rsquo;s account.</td>
			<td>Home Value: 150,000<br />
			Initial Down Payment: 5,000.<br />
			Monthly Mortgage Payment: 1,200<br />
			Total investment: 19,400</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td style="background-color:#f1f1f1"><strong>Total Assets after a year:</strong> Zero</td>
			<td style="background-color:#f1f1f1"><strong>Total Assets after a year:</strong> Any appreciation the house received during that year, plus any money that you have paid to the principal of the loan.</td>
		</tr>
	</tbody>
</table>

<p>The difference is that you are making a payment for a mortgage loan, but chances are your home value increases during a period of time. That means that if you bought the house for $150,000 after a year of making payment on that mortgage loan, you owe less than what you started with, and the house is worth more.</p>

<p>This difference you could easily see if you sold the house, as money that you receive, minus any fees for selling it.</p>

<p>One risk when buying a home is the risk of not being able to continue making monthly payments, and therefore loosing the home when the bank decides to foreclose on it.</p>

<p>This is calculated risk that we all take when making any major purchase and that although should be considered, should not deter anybody from buying a home</p>

<p>Some expenses you need to consider are property taxes and insurance. Use our <a href="http://www.premierconsumer.org/articles/credit/buying-vs-renting.php#">Mortgage Calculator</a> to find out how much of a home you can afford. Many banks and mortgage companies will allow you to include taxes and insurance payments pre-paid (included) on your mortgage payment, so that you don&rsquo;t have to pay a lump sum at the beginning of each year.</p>

<p>Please follow this <a href="http://www.premierconsumer.org/freeanalysis.php">Free Analysis Form</a> if you would like a certified credit counselor review your home purchasing possibilities.</p>

<p>One of the factors that can single handedly lower your credit score significantly is having a late mortgage payment on your credit report. Even may time more than having for example a late credit card payment. You should avoid late mortgage payment under any circumstances.</p>

<p>If you are already falling behind on your mortgage payments, look up our how to avoid foreclosure and please call us at 1.800.296.4950 for personalized advice, or fill out our <a href="http://www.premierconsumer.org/freeanalysis.php">Free Analysis Form</a> for personalized assistance.</p>
]]></contentPage></content>
