<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content><metaTitle>Attend Our Free Credit Counseling Seminars</metaTitle><metaDescription>Please contact us if you would like to either attend a seminar by yourself, or also if you would like us to come to your school, church, fair or place of employment.</metaDescription><metaKeywords>free credit seminars</metaKeywords><pageTitle>How to Register and Attend our Free Seminars</pageTitle><temp-contentPage>&lt;p&gt;Demo c data for article&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
</temp-contentPage><template>page</template><dateModified>07/21/2015</dateModified><contentPage><![CDATA[<p>Please think of the following:</p>

<p>You work 40 hours a week, and about 40 years of your life to earn a living and to make money. This is about 80 thousand hours of your entire life. You practically spend 80 thousand hours working for someone else.</p>

<p>Now, think of this: How many hours do you spend managing this money? In a sense, how many hours do you spend working for yourself, helping yourself to manage your financial life and goals?</p>

<p><img src="http://www.premierconsumer.org/images/seminars-img1.jpg" style="float:right; margin-left:5px" /></p>

<p>When we tell you about managing your money, it does not mean opening up credit card statements or making minimum payments.</p>

<p>That would be keeping yourself in debt.</p>

<p>What we mean is setting up goals for your financial life, and that you actually know when your debts will be paid off.</p>

<p>And even if you do not have any debt, are you saving enough money? Are you overspending? Are you aware of Identity theft?</p>

<p>It is not as important how much money you make, but really how you manage it and in general how well you manage your financial life.</p>

<p>Our experience shows that many people who had higher salaries, where the same people who were heavily in debt.</p>

<p>It might be a coincidence you are visiting this page, but we believe that there is a reason behind it. The reason might be that you are having financial issues, or maybe that you need to organize your financial life and don&rsquo;t know where to start, or maybe you are just curious.</p>

<p>&lt;% call blockQuote(&quot;It is absolutely free and with no obligation of any kind.&quot; ?&gt;</p>

<p>For that purpose, our organization has combined almost 10 years of experience and knowledge into a 120 minutes general information seminar. Other seminars might take longer depending on the issue at hand.</p>

<p>A selected team chosen from our certified credit counselors, our directors and volunteers will do this seminar free of charge to you community.</p>

<p>In the past, we have done seminars in churches, fairs, schools and at a consulate in the city of Miami, Florida.</p>

<p>Please contact us if you would like to either attend a seminar by yourself, or also if you would like us to come to your school, church, fair or place of employment.</p>

<p>Spend those 120 minutes doing something that in a sense is working for yourself.</p>

<p>We can custom make these seminars to any issues that might be affecting you or your community, or also any issues that you could request.</p>

<p>The general information seminar we do is composed of the following areas:</p>

<ul>
	<li>How to establish and keep a budget?</li>
	<li>How to manage debt?</li>
	<li>How to avoid bankruptcy, foreclosure and charged off debt?</li>
	<li>The advantages of financial freedom.</li>
	<li>ID theft and your privacy rights.</li>
	<li>Your financial life and technology.</li>
	<li>20-Minutes Questions and answers section.</li>
</ul>

<p>We invite you, your family and friends to spend 120 minutes of their life that could very well make a significant difference.</p>

<p>It is absolutely free and there will be no obligation or selling of anything. We do this as part of our company mission, which you can find in our Message of Directors section.</p>

<p>It is our obligation, our duty and honor to keep you well informed and financially educated.</p>

<p>We hope you will contact us for details. You can also request it by filling out our <a href="freeanalysis.php">Free analysis Form</a> or by calling us at 1.800.296.4950</p>
]]></contentPage></content>
