<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content><category>Credit Management</category><relatedQuiz></relatedQuiz><relatedPoll></relatedPoll><metaTitle>10 symptoms that you are over your head in debt</metaTitle><metaDescription>Please consider the following ten items, and see how many apply to your financial life. If six or more do, it might be a sign that your finances are not under control, and it might be a warning to greater problems.</metaDescription><metaKeywords></metaKeywords><pageTitle>10 symptoms that you are over your head in debt</pageTitle><shortDesc>Please consider the following ten items, and see how many apply to your financial life. If six or more do, it might be a sign...</shortDesc><image>../../assets/images/processed/croppedImg_14765.jpeg</image><temp-contentPage></temp-contentPage><template>article</template><dateModified>09/25/2015</dateModified><contentPage><![CDATA[<p>Please consider the following ten items, and see how many apply to your financial life. If six or more do, it might be a sign that your finances are not under control, and it might be a warning to greater problems.</p>

<p>They are not in any specific order of importance.</p>

<ol>
	<li>Some of your credit cards have charged you in the past months over-limit and late fees</li>
	<li>You owe more than 50% of your available credit</li>
	<li>Some of your credit cards are charging interest rates higher than 18%.</li>
	<li>You are using credit cards to pay daily expenses such as food, gasoline, rent, etc,.</li>
	<li>You find yourself making balance transfer between credit cards to try to keep good interest rates.</li>
	<li>You regularly send only the minimum payment on your credit cards</li>
	<li>You don&rsquo;t know exactly how much you owe in total in credit card debt.</li>
	<li>Some of your credit cards have sent you past due or collection notices.</li>
	<li>You owe many department store chains and oil company credit cards.</li>
	<li>When you get a bill from a credit card company, you experience stress that can be reflected in not wanting to open the bill immediately</li>
</ol>

<p>If you have questions about these symptoms or wish to have your situation reviewed by a certified credit counselor please request a <a href="http://www.premierconsumer.org/freeanalysis.php">Free Analysis</a> now.</p>
]]></contentPage></content>
